HUSSAIN AZIZ SAIF

+971 50 1670243 # HUSSAIN.AZIZSAIF@GMAIL.COM # DUBAI, UAE

LINKEDIN # GITHUB # PORTFOLIO

Professional Profile

Senior Computer Engineering student with a passion for technology and problem-solving. Developed programs in C++, C#, Dart, and python and created websites hosted in AWS using React and Django. Has a keen interest in machine learning and is currently working on publishing a research paper on anomalous factory machine sound detection using auto encoder neural networks.

Education

BSc Computer Engineering with minor in Data Science

at American University of Sharjah, UAE. (Expected Graduation: May 2024) **Relevant Courses**: Machine Learning, Neural Networks, Computer Security

Work Experience

Internship - December 2023 to January 2024

Marshall Radio Telemetry Gulf, Dubai, UAE

- Designed a dynamic website using *React* that displays analytics and user locations on a map.
- Developed APIs in *Django* to efficiently query the database of 4k+ users to generate analytics.

Internship – July 2023 to August 2023

Petrofac, Sharjah, UAE

 Leveraged *UI Path* to design and implement an automated process for filtering and locating invoices, enhancing operational efficiency by 80% compared to the manual processes.

Certifications

- AWS Academy Cloud Foundations Course Amazon, February 2021.
- RedHat System Administration (RH124) RedHat, January 2024.

Honors

- Tau Beta Pi Engineering Honor Society at American University of Sharjah May 2023
- IEEE Eta Kappa Nu Lambda Lambda Chapter at American University of Sharjah May 2022

Skills

- Proficient in Python, JavaScript, C++, C#, Java.
- Familiarity with keras and scikit-learn, pandas.
- Experienced with React, Avalonia UI, Flutter.
- Competent with Django, and ASP.NET.
- Strong oral and technical communication.

GPA: 3.82/4

- Creative and reliable team player.
- Effective time management and organization skills.

Projects

Lumafly – January 2023 – Ongoing (view project)

• A fully featured, cross platform desktop app written in C# which currently has 175k+ downloads.

IEEE EV race car project – September 2022 - May 2023. (view project)

Developed the car's dashboard, which displays the car's speed and other information.

Anomalous Sound Detection – September 2023 – Ongoing (view project)

Uses keras to create auto encoder neural networks for anomaly detection in factory machine sounds.
Detected anomalous sounds with 80% precision and recall.